Resume

http://coderbear.com/resume.pdf Seeking a Summer Internship

Siddharth Anil Bhagwan

siddharthabhagwan@gmail.com +1-(240)-917-9505

Over 6 years of experience in web development around products as well as services for enterprise and startups alike. Currently pursuing my masters in HCI, coupled with courses in analytics and big data this semester.

Education

MS Human Computer Interaction, University of Maryland, Aug 2016 - May 2018 GPA 4.0

B.Tech Information Technology, PEC University of Technology, India, 2006 - 2010 GPA 6.93/10

Skills

Languages - JavaScript | Ruby | HTML | CSS | Shell Scripting | XSLT | Java

Libs, Frameworks & Db - React | Rails | Bootstrap | jQuery | Skrollr | Arduino | Postgresql

Tools & Protocols - Git | REST | SOAP | Grunt | Eclipse | WebSphere MB, MQ, DataPower

Design - InVision | Prototyping | Personas | Storyboarding | Wireframing

OS & Utilities - Mac OS | Unix | Windows | Travis CI | Heroku | AWS | Google Analytics

Work Experience

DevToProd & Codemancers, Freelance Front End Engineer | May 2015 - April 2016 | Remote Design and development of front end modules, UIs using native JavaScript and frameworks like ReactJs.

Revealing Hour Creations, Senior Software Engineer | April 2014 - May 2015 | Pune, India RHC is an 8 member hardware and software startup. Crowd-funded product Tah. Front end engineering for The Incarnate Word. Organizing member of RHC Doo, Pune's only hackerspace.

Lectito, Full Stack Web Developer | Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 | Remote

Single handedly developed Lectito, a platform to share/exchange books, putting read books to use while meeting like minded people. Project dormant. Back End | Front End | UI | Dev ops.

IBM, Systems Engineer for Enterprise Integration | Aug 2010 - Feb 2013 | Pune, India

Systems Engineer for middleware in Enterprise Application Integration for Vodafone India. Experience in design, development, testing, go-live and dev ops. Projects owned - SRP | Chordiant | MSG | GDSP

Achievements & Publications

Memory Leaks in JavaScript - Designated speaker at India's first official jQuery Conf, 2015

Devmate - An open source ruby library with 3500+ downloads

Rudimentor - A web app for drummers to track their rudiments

Contribution to Open Source Projects - Noty bug fixes, Rails Framework documentation fixes

Gitanjali - Most downloaded Android app for the Nobel prize winning poem 'Gitanjali' by Tagore

Auto Deployer - Shell script utility to automate Message Broker deployments, published in iRAM, IBM

Innovation Team Award - First of a kind innovative implementation of IBM Data Power in India

Eminence and Excellence Award - Awarded by the client Vodafone for migration of a legacy module